<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Specific Topics on M. E. Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/</link><description>Recent content in Specific Topics on M. E. Mills</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>E. H. Mills and M. E. Mills General Stores</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/me-mills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/me-mills/</guid><description>&lt;p>After moving to Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners in Mar 1889, Edward restarted his general store on his own, now simply called E. H. Mills. Both Jonas and Emily clerked at E. H. Mills. Emily took over the store after Edward&amp;rsquo;s death and operated it under the name M. E. Mills from 1909 until her death in 1937. Soon thereafter, Jesse Brewer took over the store and ran it under her name for many years, primarily as a notions store with a lending library in the back. In 1961, Charles Vorhis purchased the building and moved the post office there from what is presently known as Brookton&amp;rsquo;s Market. The Mills&amp;rsquo; store structure survives today and is located at 484 Brooktondale Road.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mills’ Home in Brooktondale</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/mills-home-brooktondale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/mills-home-brooktondale/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Mills&amp;rsquo; home in Brooktondale is located at present-day (2021) 475 Brooktondale Road.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Temperance Activity</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/temperance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/temperance/</guid><description>&lt;p>The temperance movement was a significant cultural phenomenon of the mid 1800&amp;rsquo;s to the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s, and was particularly strong among the religious communities of upstate NY. There was significant overlap between members of the temperance movement and those supporting suffrage, and before that, abolition. Emily, Hannah and Ellen were all active in temperance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Emily’s Baptism</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/baptism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/baptism/</guid><description>&lt;p>07 Apr 1907, fifteen people that included Emily Mills and Jesse Brewer are baptized at Brookton Congregational Church, in a service officiated by Reverend Annis Ford Eastman on one of her last visits to Brookton.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mills Family in Corfu NY</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/corfu-eh-mills-co/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/corfu-eh-mills-co/</guid><description>&lt;p>The family moved to Corfu NY in the early 1860&amp;rsquo;s where Edward, along with partners Charles Pine and James Hillyer, started E. H. Mills &amp;amp; Co. &amp;ldquo;cash store&amp;rdquo; offering general merchandise and dry goods. Horace clerked in his father’s store, and Mary Ann was a member of First Presbyterian Church of Corfu.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mills Family in Staten Island NY</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/staten-island/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/staten-island/</guid><description>&lt;p>It appears the Mills lived in Staten Island throughout much of the 1850&amp;rsquo;s, and Edward may have lived there for a significant time prior. When the Mills married in 1850, Edward is said to be &amp;ldquo;of Factoryville&amp;rdquo;. All three Mills children were born in Staten Island. At one point, the Mills family lived with &lt;a href="https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/199802084/bartlett-brown">Bartlett Brown&lt;/a> (1833 to 24 Nov 1902), who was also in the grocery business and appears to also be a protege of &lt;a href="https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/199952123/charles-m-pine">Charles Mills Pine&lt;/a> (1812 to 8 Oct 1897). Charles Pine (who may have been related to Edward through Edward&amp;rsquo;s mother) is listed as a co-owner of E. H. Mills &amp;amp; Co. in Corfu, but it&amp;rsquo;s likely that Charles acted only as an investor, and perhaps also an adviser, in the business and was not involved in its day-to-day operation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genealogy and Long Island Origins</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/genealogy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/genealogy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edward H. Mills&amp;rsquo; ancestors were early settlers of the Town of Smithtown on Long Island and to this day the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mills_Pond_District_(St._James,_New_York)">Mills Pond District&lt;/a> is named for them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Historical Names</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/historical-names/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/historical-names/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some of the relevant historical names referenced throughout this material.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hallocks in Caroline</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/caroline-hallocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/caroline-hallocks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Although there is likely no direct connection between the two families, it is interesting to note that there are a number of Hallocks in the Danby and Caroline area coinciding with the Mills&amp;rsquo; time in the area. But obviously, if these Hallocks are related to Edward&amp;rsquo;s mother, it would certainly suggest reasons why Edward chose to move the family to Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Acknowledgements and Areas of Further Research</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/research/</guid><description>&lt;p>This research was made possible by the generosity of many people who have offered their time, access to their materials and access to their knowledge, to allow me to start putting together the puzzle pieces of Emily&amp;rsquo;s life. I apologize to those I have forgotten; these I recall in no particular order: Molly Adams, Barbara Kone, Allan Starkweather, Al Chafee, Donna Eschenbrenner, Ken Rumble, Richard Wines, Margaret Wegener, Bea Szekely, Ted Sobel, Becky Dewitt, Sarah Michelle, Ralph Conant, Carol Coggshall, Alanna Congdon, Rob Bernhardt, Lois Lounsbery, Bea Raponi, Emily Adams, Bill Besemer, Mike Scaglione, Elaine Sapp, Pastor Kayti Dean and the council of Caroline Valley Community Church. And those throughout the years who preserved precious memories: Gertrude Conant, E. D. Shurter, and Jessie Brewer.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>