<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured Articles on M. E. Mills</title>
    <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured Articles on M. E. Mills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>E. H. Mills and M. E. Mills General Stores</title>
      <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/me-mills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/me-mills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Upon moving to Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners, Edward restarted his general store, now simply &lt;em&gt;E. H, Mills&lt;/em&gt;, on his own, with his son Jonas working as clerk. Emily would eventually also work as clerk in the store, taking it over upon Edward&amp;rsquo;s death and operating it as &lt;em&gt;M. E. Mills&lt;/em&gt; until her death in 1937.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Names</title>
      <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/historical-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/historical-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of the relevant historical names referenced throughout this material.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Baptism of Emily Mills</title>
      <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/baptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;7 Apr 1907, fifteen people are baptized at Brookton Congregational Church, in a service officiated by Reverend Annis Ford Eastman on one of her last visits to Brookton. Eleven of the participants, including Emily Mills, were unmarried women.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mills Home in Brooktondale</title>
      <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/mills-home-brooktondale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/mills-home-brooktondale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mills Home in Brooktondale is located at present-day (2021) 475 Brooktondale Road.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperance Activity</title>
      <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/temperance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/temperance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The temperance movement was a significant cultural phenomena of the mid 1800&amp;rsquo;s to the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s, and was particularly strong among the religious communities of upstate NY. There was significant overlap between members of the temperance movement and those supporting suffrage, and before that, abolition. Emily, Hannah and Ellen were all active in temperance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mills Family in Corfu NY</title>
      <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/corfu-eh-mills-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/corfu-eh-mills-co/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The family moved to Corfu NY in the early 1860&amp;rsquo;s where Edward would start E. H. Mills &amp;amp; Co. general merchandise and dry goods with Charles Pine as one of his partners. Horace would clerk in the store for his father, and eventually commit suicide. Mary Ann was a member of First Presbyterian Church of Corfu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mills Family in Staten Island NY</title>
      <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/staten-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/staten-island/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It appears the Mills lived in Staten Island throughout much of the 1850&amp;rsquo;s, and Edward may have lived there for a significant time prior. When the Mills married in 1851, Edward is said to be &amp;ldquo;of Factoryville&amp;rdquo;. All three Mills children were born in Staten Island. Edward works as clerk in the grocery store of Bartlett Brown and at one time, the Mills family lives with Bartlett. Bartlett was a protege of Charles M. Pine, who may have been related to Edward through Edward&amp;rsquo;s mother.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogy and Long Island Origins</title>
      <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/genealogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/genealogy/</guid>
      <description>Genealogy Edward H. Mills has partial entries on at least two Mills family genealogies:
 Descendants of George Mills of Yorkshire and Long Island, New York at MillsAncestry.org. That site is now defunct and the contact information for it is no longer valid, however, an archived version exists, and I was able to locate its creator on Facebook to let him know about this documentation on Edward. This genealogy is dated 07 Aug 2003.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Further Research and Acknowledgements</title>
      <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/research/</guid>
      <description>Physical Artifacts Remaining The original structures of both the Mills&#39; store in Brooktondale and the Mills&#39; home in Brooktondale still exist at the time I write this.
There are relevant photos taken from the hills above and behind the Mills&#39; store that show the roof and outline of the building. The storefront of M. E. Mills is visible in the background, mostly obstructed, in photos that feature the Shurter House next door (the Shurter House sat between the Mills&#39; store and the lower bridge over Six Mile Creek in Brookton).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
