<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>M. E. Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/</link><description>Recent content on M. E. Mills</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memills.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>E. H. Mills and M. E. Mills General Stores</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/me-mills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/me-mills/</guid><description>&lt;p>After moving to Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners in Mar 1889, Edward restarted his general store on his own, now simply called E. H. Mills. Both Jonas and Emily clerked at E. H. Mills. Emily took over the store after Edward&amp;rsquo;s death and operated it under the name M. E. Mills from 1909 until her death in 1937. Soon thereafter, Jesse Brewer took over the store and ran it under her name for a dozen years, primarily as a notions store with a lending library in the back. In 1961, Charles Vorhis purchased the building and moved the post office there from what is presently known as Brookton&amp;rsquo;s Market. The Mills&amp;rsquo; store structure survives today and is located at 484 Brooktondale Road.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Edward H. Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-edward-hallock-1819/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-edward-hallock-1819/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edward Hallock Mills, born 25 Mar 1819, Smithtown NY, died 01 Jan 1908 Brookton, NY. Patriarch of the Mills family. Co-owner of &lt;a href="https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/corfu-eh-mills-co/">E. H. Mills &amp;amp; Co.&lt;/a> general store in Corfu NY and owner of &lt;a href="https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/me-mills/">E. H. Mills&lt;/a> in Motts Corners/Brookton NY.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mary Ann Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-mary-ann-1819/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-mary-ann-1819/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mary Ann (Pine) Mills, born 08 Feb 1819, Hempstead NY, died 28 Dec 1895, Brookton NY. Matriarch of the Mills family. First wife of Edward Hallock Mills, married 29 Dec 1850, Hempstead NY. Mary Ann was a devoted Presbyterian/Congregationalist.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mills’ Home in Brooktondale</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/mills-home-brooktondale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/mills-home-brooktondale/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Mills&amp;rsquo; home in Brooktondale is located at present-day (2021) 475 Brooktondale Road.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jonas E. Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-jonas-e-1852/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-jonas-e-1852/</guid><description>&lt;p>Jonas E. Mills, born 1852, Staten Island NY, died 14 October 1885, Brookton NY. Oldest child of Edward H. and Mary Ann Mills. Jonas worked as clerk in Mills&amp;rsquo; store in Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners/Brookton.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mills Family in Corfu NY</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/corfu-eh-mills-co/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/corfu-eh-mills-co/</guid><description>&lt;p>Before calling Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners home, the Mills moved to Corfu NY in the early 1860&amp;rsquo;s where Edward, along with partners Charles Pine and James Hillyer, started E. H. Mills &amp;amp; Co. &amp;ldquo;cash store&amp;rdquo; offering general merchandise and dry goods. Horace clerked in his father’s store, and Mary Ann was a member of First Presbyterian Church of Corfu.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Horace F. Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-horace-f-1854/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-horace-f-1854/</guid><description>&lt;p>Horace F. Mills, born 1854, Staten Island NY, died 27 October 1876, Corfu NY. Second child of Edward H. and Mary Ann Mills. Horace worked as clerk in E. H. Mills &amp;amp; Co., Corfu.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mills Family in Staten Island NY</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/staten-island/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/staten-island/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edward and Mary Ann began their marriage in Staten Island NY where they lived throughout the 1850&amp;rsquo;s and where all three Mills children were born. Here, Edward likely learned the grocery business from &lt;a href="https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/199952123/charles-m-pine">Charles Mills Pine&lt;/a> (1811 or 1812 to 8 Oct 1897), who eventually co-owned E. H. Mills &amp;amp; Co. in Corfu.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Emily Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-mary-emily-1858/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-mary-emily-1858/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mary Emily Mills, born Dec 1858 Staten Island NY, died 03 Nov 1937 Brooktondale NY, who commonly went by Emily, and in more formal contexts, M. Emily Mills or M. E. Mills. Youngest child of Edward Hallock and Mary Ann Mills. Proprietor, &lt;a href="https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/me-mills/">M. E. Mills&lt;/a> general store in Brookton/Brooktondale NY. Active in the &lt;a href="https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/temperance/">temperance movement&lt;/a> in the Independent Order of Good Templars and the Women&amp;rsquo;s Christian Temperance Union, as well as Sunday School teacher and piano player in Brooktonale Congregational Church, now Caroline Valley Community Church.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Genealogy and Long Island Origins</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/genealogy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/genealogy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edward H. Mills&amp;rsquo; ancestors were early settlers of Edward&amp;rsquo;s birthplace, the Town of Smithtown on Long Island, and to this day the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mills_Pond_District_(St._James,_New_York)">Mills Pond District&lt;/a> is named for them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hannah Mills</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-hannah-1824/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/mills-hannah-1824/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hannah (Thatcher) Eastman Mills, born 21 May 1824, England, died 25 Feb 1917, Brookton NY. Second wife of Edward H. Mills, married 30 Dec 1896 and step-mother to Emily. Active member of Brookton Congregational Church, Ladies&amp;rsquo; Aid Society and Women&amp;rsquo;s Christian Temperance Union.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Temperance Activity</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/temperance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/temperance/</guid><description>&lt;p>The temperance movement was a significant cultural phenomenon of the mid 1800&amp;rsquo;s to the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s, and was particularly strong among the religious communities of upstate NY. There was significant overlap between members of the temperance movement and those supporting suffrage, and before that, abolition. Emily, Hannah and Ellen were all active in temperance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ellen Gould</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/gould-ellen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/gould-ellen/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ellen Jane (Andrews) Predmore Gould, born 27 Mar 1848, died 31 Oct 1929. Ellen lived in the Mills&amp;rsquo; home, possibly for over a decade, to help care for Hannah and to help Emily with the home and store. She was a devoted member of Brookton Baptist Church and active in the temperance movement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Emily’s Baptism</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/baptism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/baptism/</guid><description>&lt;p>07 Apr 1907, fifteen people that included Emily Mills and Jesse Brewer are baptized at Brookton Congregational Church, in a service officiated by Reverend Annis Ford Eastman on one of her last visits to Brookton.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hallocks in Caroline</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/caroline-hallocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/caroline-hallocks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Although there is likely no direct connection between the two families, it is interesting to note that there are a number of Hallocks in the Danby and Caroline area coinciding with the Mills&amp;rsquo; time in the area. But obviously, if these Hallocks are related to Edward&amp;rsquo;s mother, it would certainly suggest reasons why Edward chose to move the family to Mott&amp;rsquo;s Corners.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Acknowledgements and Areas of Further Research</title><link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819-family/features/research/</guid><description>&lt;p>This research was made possible by the generosity of many people who have offered their time, access to their materials and access to their knowledge, to allow me to start putting together the puzzle pieces of Emily&amp;rsquo;s life. I apologize to those I have forgotten; these I recall in no particular order: Molly Adams, Barbara Kone, Allan Starkweather, Al Chafee, Donna Eschenbrenner, Betsy Abramson, Linda Tucker, Ken Rumble, Richard Wines, Margaret Wegener, Bea Szekely, Ted Sobel, Becky Dewitt, Sarah Michelle, Ralph Conant, Carol Coggshall, Joan Taber, Fred Estabrook, Ed Croop, Jodi Leaf, Alanna Congdon, Rob Bernhardt, Lois Lounsbery, Bea Raponi, Emily Adams, Bill Besemer, Mike Scaglione, Elaine Sapp, Pastor Kayti Dean and the council of Caroline Valley Community Church. And those throughout the years who preserved precious memories: Gertrude Conant, E. D. Shurter, and Jessie Brewer.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>