<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>M. E. Mills</title>
    <link>https://memills.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on M. E. Mills</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memills.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Family of Edward H. Mills.</title>
      <link>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/people/mills-edward-hallock-1819/</guid>
      <description>Genealogy of Edward H. Mills Edward Hallock Mills (born Smithtown NY, Mar 25, 1819, died Brookton NY, Jan 1, 1908, interred: ) Wife: Mary Ann (Pike) Mills (born Hempstead NY, Feb 8, 1819, died Brookton NY, Dec. 28, 1895)
Married: Dec 29, 1850 in Hempstead by Rev N C Locke: &amp;ldquo;Edward H Mills of Factoryville Staten Island to Mary Ann Pike of Hempstead.&amp;rdquo;
Children:
 Jonas E. Mills (born Staten Island NY, 1852, died Brookton NY, Oct 14, 1885) Horace F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/1/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:&amp;lt;A
TOMPKINS COUNTY PUBLIC LIBRARY
NaviGaTING A SEA OF RESOURCES
Title: Forests to farms in Caroline
Author: Heidt, William, comp.
Call number: LH 974.771 Heidt
Publisher: Ithaca, N.Y., Dewitt Historical Society of Tompkins County, Incorporated, 1965.
Owner: Ithaca - Tompkins County Public Library
Assigned Branch:
Collection:
Ithaca - Tompkins County Public Library (TCPL) Local History (LH)
Material type:
Number of pages:
Note:
Book 58 p. : illus., map
The History Center in Tompkins County, who owns the copyright, gave TCPL permission to digitize this book, October 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/10/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Caroline Formed in 1811
When Tompkins County was organized on April 17, 1817, it ‘was made up of parts of Seneca and Cayuga Counties. The towns of Ulysses, Covert and Hector were taken from the former, and Dryden, Lansing and Groton from the latter. The town of Caroline was not embraced by the boundaries of the new county.
Caroline, Danby and Newfield were at that time the northern tier of Tioga County towns; their territory lay within the bounds of the Watkins and Flint Tract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/12/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Offers Large Acreages for Sale
In the Ithaca Gazette and Intelligencer of June 5, 1817, the following notice indicated the acreage of land available:
TO ACTUAL SETTLERS
“About 7,000 acres of wild land in the towns of Spencer and Cayuta, Tioga County. Also 10,000 acres in the town of Elmira, Tioga County. Ben Johnson.”
Johnson was born in Haverhill, N. H., in 1784. He studied Jaw in Troy, practiced in Binghamton before coming to Hector and then to Ithaca some time before 1817.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/13/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:child born in Caroline. The next settler was the Widow Earsley who came from Roxbury, N. J., with her family of five sons and five daughters. This family arrived a week after Captain Rich.
Born Marie Jansen, Mrs. Earsley came to America from her native Holland when she was 12. Her husband was Francis Earsley, born in Ireland of English parentage, who resided at Roxbury, and was a weaver by trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/14/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Courtesy of Gertrude Conant
Erected in 1923 by the former and present residents of Caroline as a memorial in honor of the IVidow Earsley. 1s the first pioneer settler she came on horseback into this New York wilderness, purchased one hundred acres of land, and built a log cabin on this site in 1784 as a future home for herself and ten children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/15/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:there were 905 residents enumerated and others continued to come in until as late as 1838. Not all remained, but the Rich and Earsley families proved so steadfast to the soil that descendants are found there today.
Among those early families who did not take permanent roots were Thomas Tracy and son Benjamin who came in 1797, and Prince Tracy, brother of Thomas, who arrived a little later. This family moved to Owego where Benjamin F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/16/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:is dated February 22, 1797; the original document is in the DeWitt Historical Museum.
When General Cantine’s son, John Cantine, Jr., came upstate in 1798 from Ulster County, his father gave him the choice between the Chemung lands and those in Caroline. The son chose Caroline because of the waterpower possibilities offered by Six Mile Creek. Two years later his father built him a gristmill at Brooktondale, the first on the stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/17/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:at Brooktondale. He had been a soldier in the army of General Gates and had fought in both of the battles at Saratoga, but he did not witness the surrender of General Burgoyne. He had been detailed to repair a gristmill at Schuylerville that the enemy had destroyed, but was needed to grind corn for the American soldiers.
Hunting and fishing along Six Mile Creek one Sunday morning, Mulks saw for the first time the flats at Slaterville.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/18/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:falo was threatened by the British his command was ordered to the frontier; each member of his company was given a $20 gold piece and started on a march to Buffalo. At Canandaigua the unit was informed the settlement had been burned, and ordered to return home. All of Captain Slater’s soldiers felt well repaid for their walk.
During the first few years after the settlement of Slaterville, a small tribe of Oneida Indians came each fall to hunt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/19/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:But there was another increment of newcomers quite in contrast with these, for they came from Virginia and Maryland and bought large acreages from the Johnsons between 1803 and 1808. Not only did these mid-southerners bring additional skills and cultures, they brought the only large group of slaves ever introduced into the new county. A group of Southern Federalists seeking land in the Federalist North and traveling horseback, visited a large area in Central New York, then chose a location in Caroline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/2/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:he, male APY
Jere \
SOM er NT og
21K ren SM Hl A1HER,
HAI OSE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/20/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:lowed in 1808. John James Speed had been a merchant in Virginia and, with his brother, opened a store in 1805 in a log house just east of Slaterville. The next year he succeeded in having a postoffice established there and he became postmaster of Speedsville. Later he removed to Ithaca, then to Cortland, and died in Maine in 1860.
At Speedsville, the site of the oldest house is marked. It was built by Laban Jenks in 1819 and later known as the Legg Homestead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/21/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:sons were listed as follows: Hector, thirty-three; Ulysses, eighteen; Caroline, none; Danby, five. Descendants of Caroline slaves still live in the county, though slavery was outlawed nearly a century and a half ago.
A quarter mile north of the Bush Tavern site in Caroline is a marker that locates the old slave burying ground. Fourteen were buried there.
The first recorded manumission of a slave in the Town of Caroline is found in the town clerk’s book, as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/22/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:In The American Journal, an Ithaca weekly newspaper, of March 5, 1823, appears the following notice:
LOST, on Saturday 22d ult. between J. Grant’s Coffee House and the Town of Caroline, a Red Morocco POCKET-BOOK containing one $3 bill, one note of hand for twenty-three dollars, signed by Moses Hemingway, a note for nine dollars, signed by David Kingman, and my emancipation from J. J. Speed, together with some other papers of no use to any person but the owner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/23/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Native Son Became Michigan Governor
George Blair of Worcester, Mass., came into the Caroline wilderness in 1809. He was unmarried, as was Sabin Mann who came with him; later Mann married Rhoda Blackman. Drafted into the army during the War of 1812, he was killed, and Blair married his widow. It was their son Austin who became the Civil War governor of Michigan, 1861-65. Previously, he had been county clerk and prosecutor; later he served three terms as congressman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/24/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:The first tavern was opened by Richard Bush in 1801. For many years it was known as “Bush’s Stand.”
The first tannery was built by Solomon Robison and Daniel Hedges in 1816.
In 1802, Matthew Jansen brought what appeared to be the first slaves into Caroline.
The first distillery of which there is historical record was erected by Levi Slater in 1810.
The first store was opened by John James Speed, Sr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/25/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Methodist Church at Speedsville: class organized about 1820; church erected in 1851.
Methodist Church at Caroline Center: class organized about 1820; first church erected in 1825.
First Baptist Church of Caroline: organized in 1814; first church erected in 1848 at Brooktondale.
St. John’s Protestant Episcopal Church was transferred from Richford to Speedsville in 1842.
Congregational Church at Brooktondale: society formed and church built in 1868.
Universalist Church at Speedsville: built in 1828 by Methodists, Presbyterians and Universalists and used jointly until 1851; society formed in 1827, reorganized in 1870; church became property of the Universalists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/26/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:a wolf, $5; for killing a wildcat, $1.” The bounty on foxes was not specified, but at the annual town meeting in 1818 it was “Resolved, That the town law passed at annual town meeting 1817 granting one dollar bounty for fox scalps caught and killed in that town be repealed.”
Pioneers Worked with Simple Tools (With thanks to Will Osborn)
For fitting timber in building construction, there were broadaxes, chisels, augers, mauls, froes, drawshaves as well as other hand tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/27/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:stress of wind, pine sills and beams might give but oak pins held and the structure remained firm and true for many years.
These pins were made of oak or other hardwood, a block of which was stood on end and with a froe split into desired thickness for pin making. This was called “riving” and the pieces split off were known as “shakes.” Shakes were split into rough plugs that were somewhat rounded and pointed with a hand ax, and then driven into the auger holes with a large, wooden mallet or maul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/28/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Dwellings were constructed after the same pattern and much the some proportions. Space between the two center bents formed a hallway with stairs leading to the second floor, and underneath these stairs another set led to the cellar. Customarily, to one side of the hall was a large room called the parlor; to the rear of the parlor was a seldom-used bedroom for guests. On the opposite side of the hallway was a living roomkitchen where the family spent most of its indoor time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/29/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:‘When it came time for the pioneer farmer to harvest his hay, he mowed it by hand with a scythe and raked it with a hand rake. Machines were not available, and had they been their use would have been limited. Stumps and other obstructions and uneven surfaces defeated machines for many years. Grain was first cut with a sickle, the grain cradle being unusable until field obstructions were overcome. The straw lay in a regular swath which was raked by hand into sheaves that were stacked in shocks to ripen fully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/3/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/30/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:forks, hammers and other tools were shaped by blacksmiths on their anvils. These tools were heavy and cumbersome, and costly as a pound of iron brought into the new country from Hudson River furnaces cost 17 cents.
Paying for Land Difficult
After only 175 years, it can scarcely be imagined how difficult it was for farmers to pay for their lands. Most of the settlers who came into Caroline—or into the county, for that matter—were men of small means; their chief assets were determination and ability to work hard and long under adverse conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/31/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Merely recounting the story of Henry Quick conveys small information as to how he and his wife accomplished the work for which they stand credited. They worked with a small beginning; perhaps two or three acres of land were cleared each year. At first this acreage could be expected to produce little more than a subsistence let alone pay taxes, interest on indebtedness and make a token payment on the principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/32/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:the inevitable pork barrel in which the meat was preserved in salt brine. So strong became the odor of this barrel that the housewife and her family were glad when spring came so that it could be scrubbed and set in the sun to “sweeten” for use again the next fall.
Add to this collection the few pieces of furniture and other necessary items of a primitive household, one wonders how the housewife did her work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/33/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:and fields to help the men with planting, cultivation and harvest. Not only was the garden and berry patch her care, but she was largely responsible for the poultry and the dairy. With such aid as her children might give her, she assumed these outdoor duties so that the men folks might devote longer hours to the work of the fields and forests—and, perchance to her, an escape from the confines of the cabin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/34/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:barefooted. From early spring to late fall, boys and girls went barefoot; most adults did part of the time. Going shoeless for pasturing cows on frosty, late fall mornings, youngsters would chase the cows up to warm their feet where the animal had lain.
Buttons were hard to come by, so substitutes were fashioned from thread; safety pins were a later invention. Men’s pants opened at the sides and their shirts buttoned at the back; both were homemade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/35/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/35/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:with waterproof capes and coats. Rubber boots were followed by felt boots and arctics which until recent years were found occasionally in country stores. Before felt boots appeared, coarse shoes and leggings were fall and winter footwear for men and school children. All wore woolen stockings or socks through winter and into late spring.
Nearly every early home had a spinning wheel and loom, and every housewife was skilled in operating them to make the necessary fabrics for the family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/36/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Foodstuffs Mostly Home-grown
Potatoes were a year-around staple article of food. Grown plentifully in the new soil, cultivation and harvest required a minimum expenditure of time and labor; preserved easily in outdoor cellars, they kept well. A favorite method of cooking was to cover them in the ashes of the fireplace and roast them.
Wheat was a salable grain, both for flour and distilling, so it was less eaten than rye and corn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/37/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/37/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:that was plentiful in the early days when streams ran full and cold.
Persons accustomed to the use of electric lighting of today are hard put to imagine how life was endured and much work done by the primitive lighting of the cabins. At first, pine knots were used as faggots to furnish light to work by, but most unsatisfactorily for they smoked, smelled and flickered. With a small reservoir filled with lard and a wick of scrap cloth inserted and ignited, the lard lamp gave but a dim glow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/38/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/38/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:The housewife made her own yeast, and for today’s baking soda and baking powder she resorted to corn cobs. These were burned in the baking kettle and the resulting ash was a substitute for today’s leavening.
Because tea and coffee were expensive and beyond the pocketbook of the early rural family, varied substitutes were employed. Rye grain, dried peas, beechnuts, chestnuts, corn, and chickory were roasted in a pan and used in place of coffee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/39/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/39/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:pegged to the ground. Doors were roughly hewn and might be ill-fitting. Roofs were of bark or slabs of lumber roughhewn with a hand adz. Often they leaked: one newcomer to Lansing said that the only dry places in his cabin were under the table or the bed. For window panes, greased paper was used.
In the cluttered little room of the cabin, by the light of the flames in the fireplace or by faggots or pine splinters stuck in the wall of the fireplace, the housewife did her sewing, spinning and weaving; and the fathers repaired farm equipment and boots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/4/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:FORESTS TO FARMS IN CAROLINE
Compiled from various historical sources By WILLIAM HEIDT, JR. With An Introduction By W. GLENN NORRIS
Descendant of Caroline Pioneers Tompkins County Historian
1965
DeWITT HISTORICAL SOCIETY of TOMPKINS COUNTY Incorporated ITHACA, NEW YORK</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/40/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/40/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:hickory timber was frayed to form brooms; corn husks tied to a handle served the same purpose.
Among artisans essential to every pioneer community were tanners, who produced leather from homegrown hides, and coopers. The latter made containers of wood: firkins (butter tubs), kegs, and two types of barrels, “loose” and “tight.” The former type was used for storing dry products, the latter for liquids.
Democratic Society in Operation
It was a democratic society which set up the Town of Caroline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/41/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/41/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:from the uppper side of the right ear and a half-penny from the upper side of the left ear. A penny was the size of today’s 50c.
A counterpart of the New England village, the communities had a commons used by all residents. But roaming livestock were not to feed upon this sector, so laws were passed to protect the public area from trespass. At the first town meeting it was “Resolved, That swine shall not run on the commons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/42/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:men, were so inferior that they were not suggested as part of the pioneer’s equipment.
Fitting the soil on newly cleared land was a difficult task, what with stumps and roots still strongly entrenched and only improvised implements to break the soil and prepare a seed bed. For a plow a crotched limb was used to stir the recently burned-over earth to a depth of a few inches, over which grain seeds were broadcast and then “brushed-in” with a leafless branch of a tree that was hauled by hand or by an ox team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/43/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/43/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:a note in his journal concerning methods employed to remove hemlocks.
“Some of the new settlers clear the lands by beginning at tops of trees and cutting limbs. The upper ones break off the lower, and they soon strip the loftiest hemlock. We saw some of the trees trimmed that way. Others prefer making roads where the trees have been cut down, so that they can root them up. The weight of the trees in falling will remove the roots, which cannot be got rid of in cutting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/44/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/44/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Tanbark By-Product of Clearing
When Solomon Robison and Daniel Hedges built a tannery at Mott’s Corners in 1816, they contributed much to the development of Caroline. The tannery paid $4 to $6 a cord for hemlock tanbark delivered to the tanyard, and this income, small as it was, brought relief to the struggling settlers.
Not only did tanbark become a by-product of the clearing operations, it helped pay for the work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/45/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/45/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:into leather. Hemlock and white oak grew in the region, but red oak was preferred because of its greater tannin content. Oaks ranged from 8 to 10 per cent tannin; hemlock, 7 to 8 per cent. Hemlock tanning virtually came to an end in America in 1890 when British interests began to dominate the industry and specialize in oak tanning.
Where the timber was not to be used for lumber, the boles of the trees were left on the ground to decay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/46/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/46/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:largely upon young shrubs; this was called “browsing.” While traveling to his location, the newcomer fed his livestock along the way by chopping down young trees and bushes so that his animals might feed upon the twigs. This hampered travel but since it was impossible to carry an adequate supply of fodder on the trip, there was no other way for him to feed his stock. Often in drouths of later years the farmer resorted to feeding browse to keep livestock from starvation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/47/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/47/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:were other alterations in some districts and some new ones laid out so that by October 27, 1820, there were 19 school districts. Some of these embraced territory in Dryden and Danby in agreement among school commissioners of the three towns.
The new common school law made necessary some changes in the town laws, so a special meeting of the Town Board met September 27, 1813. This meeting named Gerrett Mandevell and Silas Hutchinson, inspectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/48/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/48/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:placed in the front part of the schoolroom where all the pupils might see the unfortunate one seated upon it.
A less embarrassing use of the dunce block was as an elevation for small pupils when they were reciting. They were mounted upon it so they might be seen as well as heard.
Town Lays Out Roads Early
Newcomers into the county traveled over roads that were little more than trails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/49/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/49/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:entry immediately following is dated April 27, 1811. It would appear the road in question had been laid out but not surveyed prior to the fall of 1811.
As entered in the first book of town records, surveys and alterations of highways were continuing in 1825. By that time there were some 47 roads in the young town, and these were assigned to road districts in charge of pathmasters. It was the duty of these officials to keep the roads in repair, and each spring they called out the property owners to do “road work” with men and teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/5/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:PREFACE
Caroline has been selected as a typical town of the hundreds that were carved out of the wilderness in Central New York. The people who pioneered here had their counterparts among those who conquered the forests throughout the land; they were motivated by the same desires, met the same problems and overcame them by the same means as did those who changed the face of Caroline in so few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/50/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/50/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Tin Peddlers Ride New Roads
After roads had been built, tin peddlers began their rounds through the new country. In exchange for their shiny wares they took pelts, bones and later pieces of iron, brass and other metals. Carrie Manning, in her diary of November, 1869, tells of such a transaction in these words:
“There was a tin peddler here. Ma sold a sheep pelt and got three bake tins. Em and I sold some old iron and got seven individual salt cellars and thirteen clothespins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/51/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/51/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Yo
Ning So este ff 7.
From DeWitt Museum Collection BIG BRIDGE AT MOTT’S CORNERS
As indicated by the inscription, this drawing was made November 13, 1879, by May H. Tobey. Little other information concerning the artist or bridge has come to light, as no one has been found who remembers the structure and only a few persons have personal recollections of the wielder of the pen. “May” appears to be a nickname as the census of 1850 lists her as Marion H.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/52/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/52/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:spanned West Owego Creek, which is the western boundary of the Boston Purchase and the eastern of the Watkins &amp;amp; Flint Tract. Half or the structure was in Tompkins County and half in Tioga, the dividing line being the center of the creek.
The bridge was 60 feet long and 14 wide, and substantially built of large, hewn timbers and heavy planks. The trusses were fastened to the sills with bolts that were both large and long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/53/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/53/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:The march began just north of Slaterville on a line eastward to Hunt’s Corners and westward to near Slaterville. Every man on the line advanced, firing his gun, yelling and ringing his bell. At night dry trees were set on fire at frequent intervals to frighten the predators.
It was the second Tuesday in February when the drive opened. Every man had his knapsack full of victuals and he got a fresh supply at each house he passed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/54/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/54/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Even the hand tools the farmer used were clumsy and inefficient. Like most of the tools of the day, they were the product of the local blacksmith shop whose production ranged from hoes, adzes, hammers, through door hinges and locks to bear traps. One of the latter is displayed in the DeWitt Museum along with a large collection of early tools and devices made of iron, wood and tin.
Mowing of hay was done with the scythe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/55/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/55/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:experienced hunter, kept seven families from starvation by bringing them game.
But these bees were not confined to the forest and field: women frequently arranged a spinning, quilting or sewing bee. The woman who organized a spinning bee would distribute wool among those she invited; this they spun and on the appointed day came with their skeins of yarn to knit it and visit, then join their hostess in supper. In the evening there would be dancing and games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/56/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/56/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:New Names Indicate Early Newcomers
Caroline filled up rapidly, as is indicated by the following list of residents that has been prepared from the first town clerk’s books. The roster of town officers and the town records for 1811-1824 have been searched. Not all newcomers are included because it is not likely that all families were represented on the town board or whose names appear in town records. Then, too, faded writing in the book makes it impossible to decipher several names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/57/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/57/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/58/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/58/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Nelson, John 1818
Newkirk, Daniel 1802 (1) Niver, Elisha 1834
North, Abial 1815
Norton, Isaae 1815
Norwood, Francis 1811 Norwood, Jonathan 1804 Olney, Nathaniel 1825
Park, Joseph 1814
Parmer, Rufus R. before 1825 Parsons, Isaiah 1817
Pateh, Nathan 1817
Payne, David 1811
Payne, Edward 1811
Perry, Isaiah 1825
Perry, Joseph 1820
Personius, Ephraim 1821 Prior, John before 1818 Pultze, Frederick 1820
Quick, Daniel 1804
Quick, Henry 1804
Quick, Jacobus 1815</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/59/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/59/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Where the unit of sale is not given, it is presumed the cusomary unit is understood: thus, sperm oil is sold by the gallon;
shirting, by the yard.
Pot ashes, ton, $131. Pearl ashes, ton, $140-142.50 Beef, barrels, $9.75. Beans, 7 bushels, $8.
Butter, first quality, Ib. 12-15¢.
Beeswax, yellow, Ib., 33-34¢. Bristles, American, 30-35¢. Cheese, Ib., 7-9¢.
Feathers, live, Ib. 37-45e. Flour, wheat, bbl., $7.25. Flour, rye, $3.50-4.00. Cornmeal, $3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/6/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:INTRODUCTION
Lying in the southeast part of Tompkins County is the rural town of Caroline; an upland area of high, rounded hills and pleasant valleys running in many directions.
In earlier years the town’s forest trails had been trodden for centuries by the Indian. One of the seventeen important Indian trails of the State was the Warrior’s Trail, which crossed Six Mile Creek west of Brooktondale, at the Beaverbrook Road. This crossing was just six miles from Ithaca which fact gave the stream its present name; much easier to pronounce than its Cayuga name, Teegastoweas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/60/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/60/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Roads throughout the town were still primitive dirt roads, and would remain so for nearly a century; but the Catskill turnpike, built through in 1805, and the Ithaca-Owego turnpike, completed in 1812, afforded outlets to the country’s eastern markets. Over these two roads went produce of the town to the thriving markets along the Atlantic seaboard—and the world —by way of the Susquehanna and Hudson Rivers, Erie Canal and Cayuga Lake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/61/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/61/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/62/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/62/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Mr. Goodrich was engaged in general farming and dairying
“Mr. Goodrich would train ten or twelve fine horses a year, and sell them. He kept the racetrack in use for 15 years or more until the market for horses slackened.
“Another reminder of “horse-and-buggy days” is the windbreak that Levi Goodrich made near his farm home as protection against the strong winds and heavy snows. He planted a fine grove and row of trees which stand today, after more than 60 years, as mighty patriarchs over snow and wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/63/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/63/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:manded of Speedsville of the late &amp;lsquo;80’s were provided by small, personally owned enterprises, none of which were ever thought of as lucrative businesses. Their number and the range of their services are revealing.
Seth H. Akins operated a sawmill, cheesebox factory, planing mill, cider mill; when these did not keep him busy, he did contract work, one such job being the covered bridge.
S. K. Blackman was a buyer of stock, dealer in agricultural implements and a buyer of wool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/64/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/64/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Courtesy of Charles C. Vorhis H&amp;quot;OODEN TRESTLE OVER SIX MILE CREEK Erected in 1874 to carry the Utica, Ithaca and Elmira Railroad over the Brooktondale gorge, it was constructed of foot-square timbers supplied by neighboring forests. Its efficiency as a windbreak was not fully appreciated wntil the closely spaced timbers were replaced by a spidery steel trestle in 1894. At that time, trains did not run on Sunday, a circumstance greatly favoring Moses Hurlburt who had the contract for removing the wooden trestle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/65/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/65/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Lum &amp;amp; Andrews conducted a hotel and livery.
Miss Caroline Moncrief dealt in millinery.
George H. Nixon was a shoemaker.
M. O. Owen made wooden firkins in his factory.
George R. Rounsville dealt in general merchandies.
D. P. Witter was master of Speedsville Grange 385.
W. L. Keeney was master of Speedsville Masonic Lodge 265. The Rev. Louis A. Burch was pastor of the Episcopal Church. The Rey. Arthur Osborn was pastor of the Methodist Church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/66/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/66/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:across the way from the station sprinkled the day’s plunder with phosphate whose malodorous smell overcame the delicate scents of the flowers.
Hidden around the corner of the station, a goodly number of boys and men awaited return of the collectors to the platform. The train pulled up, the bouquets were seized and the car hastily boarded. Then up went windows and out came the springtime blooms.
Determined Niece Found Long-Lost Uncle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/67/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/67/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/68/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/68/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:them trousers; they won&amp;rsquo;t button around you.” He says, “T will wear them; see here, Mary, look at these pants I am going to wear them.”
Well, I took the pants and inserted a good-sized piece in the back, and the next morning he looked a fine old gentleman, indeed. But when Laura found that he would drive a span of four-year-old colts, she almost bolted. Mother stepped in with, “Now Laura, let him drive them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/69/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/69/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:surveyors had mapped for the military township of Dryden.
One effective argument for altering the map was that of convenience. In going to Dryden to transact business residents of the seven lots were compelled to ascend South Hill, then descend into the village; the return trip was a repeat of climbing and descending in reverse order. This was done in a day when dirt roads prevailed to make the trip time-consuming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/7/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:It is timely to have a volume like the history of the Town of Caroline to remind us, in these more affluent times, of our priceless heritage, gained from the sturdy pioneers of an earlier age.
September 10, 1965 W. Glenn Norris Ithaca, New York</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/70/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/70/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:Portuguese Shanghaied Caroline Sailor
A Caroline native, who spent four years as a sailor, boasted the unusual experience of having been pressed into the army of Portugal. To obtain his release, service of the American consul were required.
He was Henry Stewart. Born in Caroline in 1817, he remained at home until he was 19, when he went to sea. During time spent in Portugal he learned the language, then traveled in Europe and Africa before returning to his native land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/8/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:CONTENTS
Caroline Formed in 1811
Offers Land for Sale .
“This Is My Home!” .
General Cantine Receives Patent Newcomers Seek Opportunities . “Yankee” and “Dutch” Sectors . Slaves in Caroline : Owners Record Slave Boy’s Birth
Native Son Becomes Michigan Governor .
Some “Firsts” in Caroline . Wildlife Imposed Burden on Settlers . Pioneers Worked with Simple Tools . Paying for Land Difficult .
Wife’s Lot Hard in Primitive Cabin, Homemade Clothing Simple Foodstuffs Mostly Homegrown .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/9/</guid>
      <description>fulltext:New Names Indicate Newcomers Prices of Pioneer Products Pioneer Era Ends
Caroline Horses Drew President’ ‘Ss 5 Carriage
Speedsville Pretty and Busy
Special Trains Visited Caroline . . Determined Niece Found Long-Lost Uncle Migration Without Motion : : Caroline Regaining Population . Portuguese Shanghaied Caroline Sailor Magnetic Waters Attract Afflicted
45
48
51 53
56
BEA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/11/</guid>
      <description>Surveyed in 1789-90 under the direction of Simeon DeWitt, surveyor general of New York State, the territory was divided into 28 townships. Each was as nearly 10 miles square as it was possible to make them and each contained 100 great lots of 600 acres each. The Land Office Commissioners began making allotments in 1790, with the requirement that actual settlement was to be made within seven years after January 1, 1790.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/trans_page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/sources/heidt-william/forests-to-farms-in-caroline/trans_page/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://memills.com/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memills.com/test/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;firstname middlename lastname&amp;rdquo; birthdate deathdate Looking for file with the naming convention:
{{ meref &amp;ldquo;adam joseph smith&amp;rdquo; 1971 }}</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
